[{"question":"Prop roots of Banyan tree are meant for","a":"Respiration","b":"Absorption of water from soil","c":"Providing support to big tree","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Branches of stem are:","a":"exogenous in origin","b":"endogenous in origin","c":"partly exogenous and partly endogenous","d":"superficial","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The leaves are modified into tendrils, hooks,  pitcher and bladder in the following plants  respectively:","a":"Sweet pea, Cat's nail, Nepenthes, Utricularia","b":"Sweet pea, Cat's nail, Utricularia, Nepenthes","c":"Nepenthes, Sweet pea, Cat's nail, Utricularia","d":"Utricularia, Nepenthes, Cat's nail, Sweet pea","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which type of function is performed by the  fleshy leaves of onion and garlic?","a":"Storage","b":"Reproduction","c":"Photosynthesis","d":"Protection","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Fibrous roots develop in maize from","a":"Upper nodes","b":"Lower nodes","c":"Upper internodes","d":"None of these","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Fibrous root system is found in:","a":"Monocotyledonous plants","b":"Dicotyledonous plants","c":"Bryophytes","d":"Gymnosperms","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Stilt roots occur in:","a":"Groundnut","b":"Rice","c":"Sugarcane","d":"Wheat","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Napiform roots are recorded from","a":"Radish","b":"Carrot","c":"Beet root","d":"Sweet potato","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Regions of roots from base to root tip are","a":"Maturation zone - Cell division zone  - Elongation zone","b":"Maturation zone - Elongation zone - Cell  division zone","c":"Cell division zone Elongation zone - Maturation zone","d":"Elongation zone - Cell division zone  - Maturation zone","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which one of the following is a fibre yielding  plant?","a":"Crotalaria juncea","b":"Cicer arietinum","c":"Triticum vulgare","d":"Impatiens balsamina","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The anthers in solanaceae are:","a":"Monothecous, introse","b":"Dithecous, extrose","c":"Dithecous, introse","d":"Monothecous, extrose","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Name the family having (9) + 1 arrangement of  stamens?","a":"Solanaceae","b":"Asteraceae","c":"Liliaceae","d":"Fabaceae","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The perianth is the term used when:","a":"androecium and gynoecium are similar","b":"androecium and calyx are similar.","c":"corolla and gynoecium are similar  .","d":"calyx and corolla are similar.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Eye of potato is:","a":"Axillary bud","b":"Accessory bud","c":"Adventitious bud","d":"Apical bud","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Flowers are sessile in","a":"Raceme","b":"Spike","c":"Corymb","d":"Umbel","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Sleeping movements commonly occur in plants  of family:","a":"Leguminosae","b":"Liliaceae","c":"Malvaceae","d":"Compositae","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Fibres are usually obtained from the members of","a":"Solanaceae","b":"Malvaceae","c":"Leguminosae","d":"Cruciferae","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"A sterile stamen is known as:","a":"Staminode","b":"Anther","c":"Pollen grain","d":"Filament","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Capitulum inflorescence is a modification of","a":"Raceme","b":"Panicle","c":"Spike","d":"Cyme","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"An example of false fruit is:","a":"Apple","b":"Pomegranate","c":"Grapes","d":"Mango","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Prop roots of Banyan tree are meant for","a":"Respiration","b":"Absorption of water from soil","c":"Providing support to big tree","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Reserve food is mainly found in:","a":"underground stems.","b":"underground modified tap roots.","c":"underground modified adventitious roots.","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The most important function of inflorescence is to help in","a":"increasing length of plant.","b":"attracting insects for cross pollination.","c":"dispersal of seeds.","d":"release of pollen grains","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"In water chestnut, the thorns are modification of:","a":"Leaflet","b":"Corolla","c":"Leaf","d":"Calyx","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"New banana plants develop from:","a":"","b":"","c":"","d":"","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"New banana plants develop from:","a":"Rhizome","b":"Sucker","c":"Stolon","d":"Seed","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The largest leaf belongs to","a":"Nerium","b":"Tobacco","c":"Victoria","d":"Rafflesia","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"A modification of leaf is:","a":"Phyllode","b":"Phylloclade","c":"Cladode","d":"Corm","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Axis between corolla and androecium is:","a":"Anthophore","b":"Gynophore","c":"Gynandrophore","d":"Androphore","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Choose the product that is derived from  style  and stigma","a":"Saffron","b":"Fenugreek","c":"Asafoetida","d":"Psyllium","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Opium is obtained from which part of the plant,  Papaver somniferum?","a":"Inflorescence","b":"Fruit (unripe)","c":"Male part (dried)","d":"Seeds","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Edible part of banana is:","a":"epicarp","b":"mesocarp and less developed endocarp.","c":"endocarp and less developed mesocarp.","d":"epicarp & mesocarp.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Edible part of banana is:","a":"epicarp","b":"mesocarp and less developed endocarp.","c":"endocarp and less developed mesocarp.","d":"epicarp & mesocarp.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Staminodes commonly occur in:","a":"Liliaceae","b":"Papilionatae","c":"Caesalpinoideae","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Velamen is found in:","a":"roots of screwpine","b":"aerial and terrestrial roots of orchids.","c":"leaves of Ficus elastica.","d":"aerial roots of orchids.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"A fibrous root system is better adapted than tap  root system for","a":"Storage of food","b":"Anchorage of plant to soil.","c":"Absorption of water and minerals","d":"Transport of water and organic food","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Buttress roots are found in:","a":"Sorghum","b":"banyan","c":"Terminalia","d":"Pandanus","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following is a modified stem for  the protection of plants from browsing animals?","a":"Tendrils","b":"Thorns","c":"Rhizome","d":"Tuber","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"A fruit developing from an inflorescence is  called:","a":"Etaerio","b":"Composite fruit","c":"Achene","d":"Berry","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The inflorescence in cauliflower is:","a":"Compound corymb","b":"Corymb","c":"Umbel","d":"Catkin","hint":"","correct":"a"}]